Legend has it that 400 years ago, Blaise Pascal made a bet.
传说在400年前  布莱斯·帕斯卡打了一个赌
"I bet I can break this large barrel of water
“我打赌  只需要另加一升水
with the weight of just one additional liter of water!"
我就能把这个盛水的大桶撑破”
"How would you do that?"
你会怎么做
"I'll pour it into a long thin tube
我会把它倒进这根细长的管子里
and the tall column of water
然后这高高的一管水
will create enough pressure in the barrel to burst it!"
就会在桶里产生足够的压强  把它炸开
"How could a little water create so much pressure?"
这么一点水  怎会产生那么大的压力呢？
"Pressure is forced over area,
压强是力与面积之比
so even a small force concentrated in a tiny area can create a huge pressure.
所以只要面积够小  很小的力也能产生很大的压强
This pressure applied at the top will squeeze the water in the barrel
施加在顶部的压强会挤压桶中的水
which will then push outwards with a huge force bursting the barrel."
并形成一股强大的外推力  把桶挤爆
My historical research suggests that
我的历史学研究表明
Pascal never actually tried bursting a barrel to test his hypothesis…
帕斯卡其实没有试过炸桶来测试他的理论
But we can!
但是我们可以！
If he's right,
如果他是对的
we can burst even the strongest barrel with just one liter of water,
再坚固的桶  我们也只需一升水就能把它撑破
provided we build a long thin and strong enough tube to pour it in.
只要我们加水的细长管足够坚固就行
"Sacré bleu, I was right!"
我的天  我是对的
sacré bleu：法语，表惊叹